# **Anthony Gentile**

# Director of Information Technology - Byram Laboratories, Inc

Collegeville, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Anthony-Gentile/096d5ba526c8a597

Experienced, motivated, and highly analytical professional with more than fifteen years of progressive IT experience seeking a Corporate IT role that will promote growth on a personal and professional level. Capable of making rational, logical, and balanced decisions and an ability to provide IT related advice to Senior Management.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Director of Information Technology**

Byram Laboratories, Inc - Branchburg, NJ - 2014 to Present

- · Execute the overall planning, organization, and operation of all company IT functions and assets
- Supervise the development of software applications and report directly to the CEO and COO providing essential strategy and policy advice that allows the sales team to plan and execute the marketing plan in an effective and successful manner
- Supervise IT support team leading to the development and deployment of software applications tailored to customer specifications
- Planned and executed the software roll-out of a new hosted energy platform including front-end and backend modules providing a richer customer experience
- Planned and executed the seamless transition of all IT related functions of two acquired companies
- Architected and supervised the implementation of a MySQL database system improving query performance and storage capacity while reducing server load
- Work with finance team to maintain an annual yearly IT budget
- Provide tier 2 support to the AMI team on technical and strategic issues resulting in an expeditious and satisfying customer support experience

# **System Administrator**

Byram Laboratories, Inc - Branchburg, NJ - 2009 to 2014

- Designed and implemented circuitry and board layout for a water meter pulse counter LCD display system and a pulse output retrofit to existing meters resulting in multiple new products
- · Lead project manager for several AMI projects involving various municipalities and military bases
- Managed the EnergyAxis Metering Automation Server platform for more than thirty accounts
- Provided on-site technical support and analysis for multiple AMI projects
- Planned and implemented disaster recovery procedures for critical company systems and data
- Designed and deployed virtualization solutions for critical company applications consolidating fourteen physical systems into just two with redundancy
- Designed, built, configured, and supported several custom servers critical to company operations

### **Engineering Technician**

Howman Engineering - Lebanon, NJ - 2000 to 2009

- Assisted senior engineer in developing a new digital stamp board control
- Developed assembly and test procedures streamlining the production process while helping minimize production errors
- Assembled, inspected, and tested industrial control circuit boards and control boxes

- Designed and implemented custom Linux NAS solution for secure and redundant storage of all digital company assets
- Provided software and hardware support for all company IT assets

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering**

Rutgers School of Engineering, Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Operating system configuration, administration, and maintenance experience with Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, Slackware, and Fedora Linux distros), Windows XP/7/8/10, Windows Server [...] legacy MS Windows versions, and MS DOS
- Hardware deployment, configuration, and troubleshooting of Dell, HP, Lenovo, Ubiquiti, and Cisco products including workstation, mobile, server, and network platforms
- Designing, configuring, deploying, and maintaining VMware ESXi 4.x/5.x and VMware Server 2.0 environments
- Deployment and configuration of Barracuda Networks products
- Router deployment and configuration including Cisco, SonicWALL, and pfSense platforms
- · Architecting, configuring, and deploying MySQL and Microsoft SQL relational database systems
- HTTP, PHP, Python, MySQL, UNIX shell, Java, and C programming/scripting languages